A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 25 FA297
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 25
1928-1950
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
FA297
9.12 Cubic Feet 24 letter document boxes
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement note
This series is arranged in four subseries:
Subseries 1 - Conferences
Subseries 2 - Fellowships
Subseries 3 - Special Projects
Subseries 4 - Special Studies
Biographical/Historical note
The Commonwealth Fund was established in 1918 with an endowment of $10 million from Mrs. Stephen V. Harkness for "benevolent, religious, educational and like purposes." The early grants supported a variety of programs while generally promoting welfare, especially child welfare. Several grants were made in the field of medical research, but the Board of Directors decided in 1920 that this field was already sufficiently supported by other philanthropic organizations.
Despite this decision, by the mid-1920s the chief interest of the Fund had become public health, including mental hygiene, community health, rural hospitals, medical research, and medical education. Other grant areas included war relief, educational and legal research, child welfare, and international medical fellowships.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IX; IV 4B 4
Scope and Contents note
Throughout the 1930s and 1940s the Commonwealth Fund provided financial support for several unique projects concerning psychiatry, pediatrics, and the teaching/training of psychiatrists. Public and private institutions, as well as individuals, were recipients of these grants, with the majority going to universities and colleges. The records for the special studies consist mainly of correspondence and general files relating to a specific grant. Financial records are also found in the folders titled "General Files and Correspondence." A list of the original Commonwealth Fund code assigned to the grants is available in the print version of the finding aid.
Other Finding Aids
Other available finding aids describing the Commonwealth Fund records include:
FA247 Commonwealth Fund Harkness House drawings
FA276 Commonwealth Fund records, Annual Reports, SG 1, Series 4
FA277 Commonwealth Fund records, Archives/Library, SG 1, Series 5
FA278 Commonwealth Fund records, Austrian Program, SG 1, Series 6
FA279 Commonwealth Fund records, Board of Directors, SG 1, Series 7
FA280 Commonwealth Fund records, Capital Grants, SG 1, Series 8
FA281 Commonwealth Fund records, Child Health Demonstrations, SG 1, Series 9
FA282 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Community Clinics, SG 1, Series 10
FA283 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Health Studies, SG 1, Series 11
FA284 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Public Health, SG 1, Series 12
FA285 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Publications, SG 1, Series 13
FA286 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Rural Hospitals, SG 1, Series 14
FA287 Commonwealth Fund records, Educational Research, SG 1, Series 15
FA288 Commonwealth Fund records, English Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 16
FA289 Commonwealth Fund records, Finance Committee, SG 1, Series 17
FA290 Commonwealth Fund records, Grants, SG 1, Series 18
FA291 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Family, SG 1, Series 19
FA292 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, SG 1, Series 20
FA428 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, Fellows Reports, SG 1, Series 20A
FA293 Commonwealth Fund records, Institute for Child Guidance, SG 1, Series 21
FA294 Commonwealth Fund records, Interface Program, SG 1, Series 22
FA295 Commonwealth Fund records, Legal Research Program, SG 1, Series 23
FA296 Commonwealth Fund records, Living at Home Program, SG 1, Series 24
FA297 Commonwealth Fund records, Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 25
FA298 Commonwealth Fund records, Miscellaneous - unprocessed
FA299 Commonwealth Fund records, Personnel - unprocessed
FA300 Commonwealth Fund records, Pilgrim Trust, SG 1, Series 28
FA301 Commonwealth Fund records, Program for the Prevention of Delinquency, SG 1, Series 29
FA302 Commonwealth Fund records, Reference Files, SG 1, Series 30
FA303 Commonwealth Fund records, Reports of the General Director, SG 1, Series 31
FA304 Commonwealth Fund records, Treasurer, SG 1, Series 32
FA305 Commonwealth Fund records, Turndown Lists, SG 1, Series 33 - unprocessed
FA306 Commonwealth Fund records, Vertical File (R. Fitz), SG 1, Series 34 - unprocessed
FA307 Commonwealth Fund records, Visual Materials, SG 1, Series 35
FA389 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Historical Files, SG 1, Series 1
FA390 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Officers Files, SG 1, Series 2
FA429 Commonwealth Fund records, President, Margaret E. Mahoney, SG 2, Series 1
FA430 Commonwealth Fund records, Book Program, SG 2, Series 2
War relief; New York (State); Public health; Public welfare; United States; Child welfare; Child psychology; Child mental health; New York (N.Y.); Law; Legal issues; Education, Rural; Hygiene; Medical research; Medicine, Rural; Legal research; Medical education; Medicine -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Mental health
- Conferences, 1944-1948; 1; 1 box(es)
  Arrangement note
  This subseries is arranged alphabetically by project.
  - Hershey Conference on Comprehensive Pediatrics - Pediatric-Psychiatric Teaching and Training (March 6-8, 1947) - Conference Agenda and Materials, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hershey Conference on Comprehensive Pediatrics - Pediatric-Psychiatric Teaching and Training (March 6-8, 1947) - Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hershey Conference on Comprehensive Pediatrics - Pediatric-Psychiatric Teaching and Training (March 6-8, 1947) - Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hershey Conference on Comprehensive Pediatrics - Pediatric-Psychiatric Teaching and Training (March 6-8, 1947) - Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hershey Conference on Comprehensive Pediatrics - Pediatric-Psychiatric Teaching and Training (March 6-8, 1947) - Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hershey Conference on Comprehensive Pediatrics - Pediatric-Psychiatric Teaching and Training (March 6-8, 1947) - Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hershey Conference on Comprehensive Pediatrics - Pediatric-Psychiatric Teaching and Training (March 6-8, 1947) - Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hershey Conference on Comprehensive Pediatrics - Pediatric-Psychiatric Teaching and Training (March 6-8, 1947) - Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hershey Conference on Comprehensive Pediatrics - Pediatric-Psychiatric Teaching and Training (March 6-8, 1947) - Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hershey Conference on Comprehensive Pediatrics - Pediatric-Psychiatric Teaching and Training (March 6-8, 1947) - Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hershey Conference on Post-War Psychiatric Needs (February 1-3, 1945) - General Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hershey Conference on Post-War Psychiatric Needs (February 1-3, 1945) - General Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Hershey Conference on Post-War Psychiatric Needs (February 1-3, 1945) - General Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hershey Conference on Post-War Psychiatric Needs (February 1-3, 1945) - Steering Committee - General Correspondence, April-October (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Conferences on Training and Fellowships in Child Psychiatry (October 12-13, 1944; December 27-28, 1944; December 17-18, 1945) - General Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Conferences on Training and Fellowships in Child Psychiatry (October 12-13, 1944; December 27-28, 1944; December 17-18, 1945) - General Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Fellowships, 1925-1983; 2; 11 box(es)
  - Boston Psychopathic Hospital - General and Financial Correspondence, 1931-1934 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Commonwealth Fund Fellowships at Large (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Scope and Contents note
    Alpern, Evelyn - January 19, 1931-July 28, 1933 Freeman, Rowland G., Jr. - April 1, 1930-May 31, 1933
  - Commonwealth Fund Fellowships at Large - Hardcastle, Noel, 1929-1933 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Commonwealth Fund Fellowships at Large (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Holmer, Paul - August 4, 1930-July 28, 1933 Huschka, Mabel - September 29, 1930-June 27, 1933
  - Commonwealth Fund Fellowships at Large (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Jewel, Arthur - July 28, 1931-July 28, 1933 Levine, Maurice - January 25, 1932-June 30, 1933
  - Commonwealth Fund Fellowships at Large (Box 2, Folder 22)
    McIntosh, Ronald B. - December 15, 1930-August 29, 1932 Murray, John M. - December 11, 1929-September 2, 1930
  - Commonwealth Fund Fellowships at Large - Osborne, Wilmoth, 1930-1932 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Fellowships in Psychiatry for Pediatricians - Applications (A-I), 1939-1947 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Fellowships in Psychiatry for Pediatricians - Applications (J-R), 1939-1947 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Fellowships in Psychiatry for Pediatricians - Applications (S-Z), 1939-1947 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Fellowships in Psychiatry for Pediatricians - Awards - Bruton, Ogden C., 1937-1940 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Fellowships in Psychiatry for Pediatricians - Awards - Little, Sherman, 1937-1940 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Fellowships in Psychiatry for Pediatricians - Awards - Schade, George H., 1937-1940 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Fellowships in Psychiatry for Pediatricians - Awards - Senn, Milton, 1937-1939 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Fellowships in Psychiatry for Pediatricians - General Files, 1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - General Data - General Files and Memoranda [21-6 and 21-6-R], 1927-1932 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Ham, George C. - General Files and Correspondence, 1944-1951 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Ham, George C. - General Files and Correspondence, 1944-1951 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Henry Phipps Psychiatric Clinic - Fellowships in Psychiatry - General and Financial Correspondence, 1928-1949 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Henry Phipps Psychiatric Clinic - Fellowships in Psychiatry - General and Financial Correspondence, 1928-1949 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Henry Phipps Psychiatric Clinic - Fellowships in Psychiatry - General and Financial Correspondence, 1928-1949 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Henry Phipps Psychiatric Clinic - Fellowships in Psychiatry - General and Financial Correspondence, 1928-1949 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Henry Phipps Psychiatric Clinic - Fellowships in Psychiatry - General and Financial Correspondence, 1928-1949 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Henry Phipps Psychiatric Clinic - Fellowships in Psychiatry - General and Financial Correspondence, 1928-1949 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Henry Phipps Psychiatric Clinic - Fellowships in Psychiatry - General and Financial Correspondence, 1928-1949 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Henry Phipps Psychiatric Clinic - Fellowships in Psychiatry - Teaching Material [Dr. John C. Whitehorn], June 1943 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Institute for Child Guidance - Fellowships - Psychiatrists (A-B), 1927-1932 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Institute for Child Guidance - Fellowships - Psychiatrists (C-E), 1927-1932 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Institute for Child Guidance - Fellowships - Psychiatrists (G-K), 1927-1932 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Institute for Child Guidance - Fellowships - Psychiatrists (L-P), 1927-1932 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Institute for Child Guidance - Fellowships - Psychiatrists (R-S), 1927-1932 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Institute for Child Guidance - Fellowships - Psychiatrists (T-W), 1927-1932 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Institute for Child Guidance - Fellowships - Psychologists (B-H), 1927-1932 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Institute for Child Guidance - Fellowships - Psychologists (K-N), 1927-1932 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Institute for Child Guidance - Fellowships - Psychologists (P-Y), 1927-1932 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Institute for Child Guidance - Fellowships - Financial Data and Correspondence, 1927-1933 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Institute for Child Guidance - Fellowships - Financial Data and Correspondence, 1927-1933 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Institute for Child Guidance - Fellowships - General Correspondence - Psychiatrists, 1928-1932 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Institute for Child Guidance - Fellowships - General Correspondence - Psychologists, 1928-1931 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Institute of the Pennsylvania Hospital - Post-War Psychiatric Fellowships - General Files and Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Institute of the Pennsylvania Hospital - Post-War Psychiatric Fellowships - General Files and Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Institute of the Pennsylvania Hospital - Post-War Psychiatric Fellowships - General Files and Correspondence, 1947-1949 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Jensen, Reynold A. - Fellowship in Child Psychiatry - General and Financial Correspondence, 1942-1948 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Traveling Fellowships - General Correspondence, 1929-1932 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1935-1941 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1935-1941 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1935-1941 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1935-1941 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1935-1941 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1935-1941 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1935-1941 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1935-1941 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1935-1941 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1935-1941 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1935-1941 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1935-1941 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1942-1950 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1942-1950 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1942-1950 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1942-1950 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1942-1950 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene - Division of Community Clinics - Child Guidance Fellowships - Correspondence, Finances and Reports, 1942-1950 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - National Committee on Visiting Teachers - Correspondence and Applications, 1928-1929 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - National Committee on Visiting Teachers - Correspondence and Applications, 1928-1929 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - New York School of Social Work - Fellowships in Psychiatric Social Work - Financial Data, 1928-1950 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - New York School of Social Work - Fellowships in Psychiatric Social Work - Financial Data, 1928-1950 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - New York School of Social Work - Fellowships in Psychiatric Social Work - Financial Data, 1928-1950 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - New York School of Social Work - Fellowships in Psychiatric Social Work - General Correspondence and Reports, 1927-1940 (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - New York School of Social Work - Fellowships in Psychiatric Social Work - General Correspondence and Reports, 1927-1940 (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - New York School of Social Work - Fellowships in Psychiatric Social Work - General Correspondence and Reports, 1927-1940 (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - New York School of Social Work - Fellowships in Psychiatric Social Work - General Correspondence and Reports, 1941-1950 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - New York School of Social Work - Fellowships in Psychiatric Social Work - General Correspondence and Reports, 1941-1950 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - Philadelphia Child Guidance Clinic - Training in Psychiatry - General Correspondence, 1935-1946 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - Philadelphia Child Guidance Clinic - Training in Psychiatry - General Correspondence, 1935-1946 (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Miscellaneous (A-C), 1979-1983 (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Miscellaneous (D-H), 1929-1949 (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Miscellaneous (J-M), 1929-1949 (Box 7, Folder 93)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Miscellaneous (N-P), 1929-1949 (Box 7, Folder 94)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Miscellaneous (R-Y), 1929-1949 (Box 7, Folder 95)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Psychiatric Social Work (A-C), 1929-1949 (Box 7, Folder 96)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Psychiatric Social Work (D-G), 1929-1949 (Box 7, Folder 97)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Psychiatric Social Work (H-L), 1929-1949 (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Psychiatric Social Work (M-P), 1929-1949 (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Psychiatric Social Work (R-S), 1929-1949 (Box 7, Folder 100)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Psychiatric Social Work (T-W), 1929-1949 (Box 7, Folder 101)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Psychiatrists and Psychologists (A-C), 1929-1949 (Box 7, Folder 102)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Psychiatrists and Psychologists (D-G), 1929-1949 (Box 8, Folder 103)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Psychiatrists and Psychologists (H-L), 1929-1949 (Box 8, Folder 104)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Psychiatrists and Psychologists (M-P), 1929-1949 (Box 8, Folder 105)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Psychiatrists and Psychologists (R-S), 1929-1949 (Box 8, Folder 106)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Psychiatrists and Psychologists (T-Z), 1929-1949 (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - Requests for Information on Fellowships - Visiting Teachers (B-W), 1929-1949 (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - Smith College School for Social Work - Fellowships in Psychiatric Social Work - Financial Data, 1927-1948 (Box 8, Folder 109)
  - Smith College School for Social Work - Fellowships in Psychiatric Social Work - General Correspondence and Reports, 1925-1948 (Box 8, Folder 110)
  - Smith College School for Social Work - Fellowships in Psychiatric Social Work - General Correspondence and Reports, 1925-1948 (Box 8, Folder 111)
  - Smith College School for Social Work - Fellowships in Psychiatric Social Work - General Correspondence and Reports, 1925-1948 (Box 8, Folder 112)
  - Smith College School for Social Work - Fellowships in Psychiatric Social Work - General Correspondence and Reports, 1925-1948 (Box 8, Folder 113)
  - Smith College School for Social Work - Fellowships in Psychiatric Social Work - General Correspondence and Reports, 1925-1948 (Box 8, Folder 114)
  - Smith College School for Social Work - Fellowships in Psychiatric Social Work - General Correspondence and Reports, 1925-1948 (Box 8, Folder 115)
  - Society of the New York Hospital - Fellowships for Training in Child Psychiatry (Box 9, Folder 116)
    Coleman, Rose - June 24, 1947-September 2, 1947 Crutcher, Roberta - June 18, 1941-August 7, 1942 Daly, Mary - March 23, 1943-September 23, 1943 Erganian, Jane - March 28, 1944-April 5, 1944 Fraser, Alan W. - October 9, 1945-December 11, 1947
  - Society of the New York Hospital - Fellowships for Training in Child Psychiatry - Galenson, Eleanor, 1943-1946 (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - Society of the New York Hospital - Fellowships for Training in Child Psychiatry - General and Financial Files, 1940-1948 (Box 9, Folder 118)
  - Society of the New York Hospital - Fellowships for Training in Child Psychiatry - General and Financial Files, 1940-1948 (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - Society of the New York Hospital - Fellowships for Training in Child Psychiatry - Institute of Child Development, 1947-1948 (Box 9, Folder 120)
  - Society of the New York Hospital - Fellowships for Training in Child Psychiatry (Box 9, Folder 121)
    Lulow, William - March 1, 1946-January 24, 1950 McKnight, W. K. - December 30, 1937-January 11, 1946
  - Society of the New York Hospital - Fellowships for Training in Child Psychiatry (Box 9, Folder 122)
    Mercer, Mary - October 17, 1945-April 18, 1950 Peck, Harris - September 24, 1945-November 17, 1945 Prugh, Dane - June 2, 1944-September 18, 1946 Rockwell, Elizabeth - October 2, 1942-October 1, 1943
  - Society of the New York Hospital - Fellowships for Training in Child Psychiatry (Box 9, Folder 123)
    Wolf, Richard - October 17, 1945-June 28, 1948 Woodward, Walter - January 26, 1944-September 12, 1947
  - Society of the New York Hospital - Fellowships for Training in Child Psychiatry (Box 9, Folder 124)
    Work, Henry - October 17, 1945-April 7, 1947 Wright, Harold - July 14, 1942-November 21, 1945
  - Society of the New York Hospital - Fellowships for Training in Child Psychiatry - Zimmerman, Kent, 1940-1946 (Box 9, Folder 125)
  - Society of the New York Hospital - Payne Whitney Psychiatric Clinic - Fellowships for Basic Training in Psychiatry - General Files and Correspondence, 1942-1945 (Box 9, Folder 126)
  - Special Psychiatric Fellowships - Advanced Special Training - Bochner, Alfred, 1946-1948 (Box 9, Folder 127)
  - Special Psychiatric Fellowships - Advanced Special Training (Box 9, Folder 128)
    Brewster, Henry - February 2, 1946-June 30, 1947 Cammer, Leonard - March 30, 1946-January 5, 1948 Crocker, David - January 31, 1946-June 23, 1948
  - Special Psychiatric Fellowships - Advanced Special Training (Box 9, Folder 129)
    deHoff, John - January 5, 1946-October 1, 1946 Lerner, Samuel - April 29, 1946-October 19, 1948 Matthews, Bernard - December 16, 1948-July 5, 1949 Prugh, Dane - September 28, 1946-December 8, 1955
  - Special Psychiatric Fellowships - Advanced Special Training (Box 9, Folder 130)
    Redmon, William - March 11, 1948-March 31, 1949 Stewart, Walter - March 11, 1948-October 24, 1947